[Music]
when i was a child i like to imagine
that fairies brought about the change of
seasons
a little pixie planted spring wildflower
seeds
lord summersprite coaxed the sun rays
over the meadow
and a sweet old autumn gnome gathered
the harvest
and then there was the snow fairy i
still think of her in particular
as her image has stayed with me
throughout the years
i always imagine her riding a rabbit she
has long curly hair
and mysterious melancholy eyes
she was often misunderstood by the other
fairies who feared her strange looks
and ways so they would banish her to the
highest mountain peaks
when her time was over to wait in a
lonely ice cave
until she could return again
naturally this made the fairy feel quite
unwelcomed
as she longed to visit the other seasons
and discover their treasures
she dreamt of wandering flower fields
barefoot and tasting the crisp sweetness
of fall fruit
but the other fairies were uninviting
fearing her frosty fingers would wither
anything she touched
[Music]
the snow fairy was hurt and the next
time she was sent to the mountains of
eternal winter to wait out the year
she vowed never to return why should she
no one cared no one wanted her in the
land below
[Music]
my
sequestered in the mountains the snow
fairies spent her days casting spells of
frost
raining snowflakes and summoning
blizzards
it was a beautiful world she created the
landscape was a tapestry she wove with
ice
and crystal here where the air was thin
she felt safe there were no fairies or
townspeople to grumble at the snow
wishing for spring to come sooner yes
the fairy would stay in her mountains
this would please everyone
she thought
but when the cold was supposed to come
to the rest of the land
it didn't the open fields were untouched
by snowflakes
lake water unfrozen the open sky
blue and cloudless that year the land
suffered from lack of water
and the other fairies could not fulfill
their duties
the parched land was infertile something
had to be done
the fairies pleaded with woodland
animals hoping some beast would be brave
enough to scale the mountains
and call back the snow fairy it is too
cold for us they said
we will freeze our toes and get lost in
the blizzard
and even if we did find her she would
not listen to us
we who were so cold and cruel to her
and sent her away
i will go and fetch her said the rabbit
he was small but courageous
and unafraid of snowdrifts but even the
hardiest of rabbits cannot scale
a mountain slope and when he finally
reached the ferry he had only one breath
left in his little body
he told her that the land was dying
without her help
and that she had to return and that he
missed her dearly
and with that he closed his eyes
the fairy wept over the noble rabbit as
she had never wet before
her heart which had been safely locked
away for so long
broken too you may not know this but
when a fairy's heart breaks the special
magic is released
one that can grant his single wish the
fairy held the wisp of pixie dust in her
palm and was tempted to wish for a
winter that would come and go without
her assistance
she could then stay in the mountains
forever away from all that caused her
pain
but that was not what the fairy did
because in its broken state
her heart had felt love for the very
first time
[Music]
now each year once the harvest has been
gathered the snow fairy begins her long
trek down from her mountain
carrying a basket of snowflakes to
spread over the countryside
her job is difficult and there are those
who still don't enjoy her visits
but she no longer hears their words and
now
she has a friend to accompany her
because if you ever catch a glimpse of
the snow fairy through your window
as the frost sets in on wintertide's eve
you will see that a small rabbit trail
is behind her
following her steps and gazing in awe at
the beauty of her snowy world
you